Finding aid for the Sylvia Plath collection MRBC.MS.00045
Mortimer Rare Book Collection
- Ted Hughes, 1930-1998; 13; 5.33 linear feet (8 boxes; 3 oversize folders; 1 folder in another series)
  - Birthday Letters (Box 36, Box 37, Box 38)
    These items are arranged alphabetically, primarily by the name of the publication in which they appear.
- Olwyn Hughes, 1972-1978; 14; .2 linear feet (1 box) (Box 39)
  This series contains correspondence, primarily between Olwyn Hughes (Ted Hughes' sister) and London publisher Peter Owen, concerning a proposed book of recollections of Sylvia Plath, to be edited by Lois Ames. Some of the correspondence also concerns changes in a book about Plath by Edward Butscher.
  The correspondence is arranged in chronological order.
  Purchased from Clayton Fine Books (McConnell-Bohning Fund), 2011.
- Marcia Brown Stern, approximately 1966-2000; 15; .5 linear feet (1 box) (Box 40)
  Books from the library of Marcia Brown Stern including books by and about Sylvia Plath, some annotated and with mounted photographs by Marcia B. Stern.
  Items in this series were donated 02/16/2012 by Marcia Brown Stern, Smith College class of 1954.
  Biographical / Historical
- Writings of others collected and edited by Sylvia Plath, approximately 1953-1961; 16; .2 linear feet (1 box) (Box 41)
  This series contains American Poetry Now (Critical Quarterly Poetry Supplement number 2), edited by Sylvia Plath (proofs and printed copies). It also has typescripts, clippings, and reprints of writing by others collected by Sylvia Plath. Some items have manuscript annotations by Plath. Details about the items are written on each folder. Some of these poems were included in American Poetry Now. There are also some notes by researchers relevant to this material.
  Arranged alphabetical by author last name following copies and proofs of American Poetry Now.
- Writing, artwork, and memorabilia of others, approximately 1950-2007; 17; 2.2 linear feet (1 box; 1 oversize folder) (Box 42, Box 44, Folder 9)
  This series contains items relating to Sylvia Plath, created or collected by various people.